Guide to the Adele Fournet Papers on the Bit Rosie Web Series MSS.460
Fales Library and Special Collections
Adele Fournet Papers on the Bit Rosie Web Series
2015-2016
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fournet, Adele
MSS.460
715.37 Gigabytes in 35 computer files and 1 archived website.
715.06 Gigabytes in 35 computer files.
309.1 Megabytes in 1 archived website.
Bit Rosie is a web series about female music producers directed, produced, and edited by Adele Fournet between 2015 and 2016. The project sought to highlight the work of women creating electronic music and to disseminate their work. The Adele Fournet Papers on the Bit Rosie Web Series include 33 video recordings created by Fournet and the website, bitrosie.com, on which the recordings were posted. The recordings include full-length and edited interviews with and performances by 11 of the 12 female music producers and groups featured on bitrosie.com. The Bit Rosie website includes the edited interviews and video recordings of performances. The interviews include discussions of the type of music the women create and produce, their creative influences and processes, and their feelings about being women in a male-dominated field.
Scope and Contents
The Adele Fournet Papers on the Bit Rosie Web Series documents the work of Fournet in creating her web series, Bit Rosie, about female music producers. The collection contains 33 video recordings recorded by Fournet; an archived copy of bitrosie.com, the website on which the series was published; and two spreadsheets created by Fournet with information about each producer. The video recordings include full-length and edited interviews with and performances by 11 of the 12 female music producers featured on bitrosie.com. The producers represented in the collection are Klara Andersson, Orieta Chrem, Julie Covello, Friederike Jäger, Julie Kathryn, Minami Kato, K. Marie Kim, Dion McKenzie, Franziska Plückhan, Pauchi Sasaki, and Gisela Fullá Silvestre. The interviews include discussions of the type of music the women create and produce, their creative influences and processes, and their feelings about being women in a male-dominated field. The interviews were conducted in New York, Germany, and Peru. The website includes brief biographies, edited interviews, and video recordings of performances for 12 female music producers. The spreadsheets include information about the producers, including the type of music they create, the hardware and software they use to create the music, and where they live and work.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order by last name of the music producer or format of material.
Historical Note
Bit Rosie is a web series about female music producers directed, produced, and edited by Adele Fournet between 2015 and 2016. The project sought to highlight the work of women creating electronic music and to disseminate their work. Fournet conducted 12 interviews with women working with music technology as producers, DJs, and engineers, both individually and in collaboration with other women. The interviews were conducted between 2015 and 2016 in New York, Germany, and Peru.
Conditions Governing Access
Edited interviews and video recordings of performance videos are available for public streaming from NYU Libraries' website. The full-length interviews are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval from the NYU Libraries based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Adele Fournet, September 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.041.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archiveit.org/organizations/567
Appraisal
Duplicate video recordings were removed.
Take-down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information. If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials. If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to fales.library@nyu.edu. Please include the following in your notice: identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Custodial History
Websites are selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Composition (Music) -- 21st century.; Electronic music.; Music -- Peru -- 20th century.; Women musicians -- Interviews.; Video recordings.; Music -- Germany -- 20th century.; Music -- New York (State) -- New York -- 20th century.; Bit Rosie
- Adele Fournet Papers on the Bit Rosie Web Series
  - Andersson, Klara, 2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Biographical
    Klara Andersson is a Swedish music composer and performer who utilizes traditional instruments along with technological enhancements to produce her pieces, which seek to explore the line between noise and music. She works under the stage name Fagelle.
    - Andersson, Klara -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5743; 3.95 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_1)
    - Andersson, Klara -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5742; 46.81 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_13)
      Conditions Governing Access
      This video recording is available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
    - Andersson, Klara -- Performance, 2016; cuid5744; 6.43 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_32)
  - Archived website, 2017-ongoing (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Accruals
    New site crawls are accrued quarterly.
    Existence and Location of Originals
    The url of the archived website was http://www.bitrosie.com at the time of capture.
  - Chrem, Orieta, 2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Orieta Chrem is a member of Menores, an experimental hip-hop group based in Lima, Peru. She is also the producer of the group's music.
    - Chrem, Orieta -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5746; 3.52 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_14)
    - Chrem, Orieta -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5745; 39.17 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_17)
    - Chrem, Orieta -- Performance, 2016; 3 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_2)
  - Covello, Julie, 2015-2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Julie Covello, working under her stage name "DJ Shakey", is the producer for a freestyle musical duo based out of Brooklyn, NY, called Opal Crocus. She also has a solo career as a composer and performer.
    - Covello, Julie -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5749; 5.27 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_4)
    - Covello, Julie -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5748; 66.31 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_3)
    - Covello, Julie -- Performance, 2015; cuid5750; 4.36 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_8)
  - Inventories, 2016; 13.81 kilobytes in 2 spreadsheets. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_9)
  - Jäger, Friederike, 2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Friederike Jager is a composer and performer based in Berlin, Germany. She composes musical works with strong visual components as well as producing music for theater.
    - Jäger, Friederike -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5752; 3.96 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_10)
    - Jäger, Friederike -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5751; 27.79 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_15)
    - Jäger, Friederike -- Performance, 2016; cuid5753; 2.87 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_5)
  - Kathryn, Julie, 2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Julie Kathryn is a music composer, producer, and performer based in New York City. She is also on of the lead producers of the group "Female Frequency", an organization dedicated to encouraging women to make music. She has composed and performed under her own name as well as the stage name "I Am Snow Angel", which designates her exploration of a mre pop-electronic style of music.
    - Kathryn, Julie -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5755; 2.96 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_16)
    - Kathryn, Julie -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5754; 48.62 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_6)
    - Kathryn, Julie -- Performance, 2016; cuid5756; 3.18 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_18)
  - Kato, Minami, 2015 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Minami Kato is a Japanese composer and producer based in Brooklyn, NY. Her love for technology and music shape her creations, although she also plays several traditional instruments.
    - Kato, Minami -- Edited interview, 2015; cuid5758; 4.22 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_19)
    - Kato, Minami -- Full-length interview, 2015; cuid5757; 46.69 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_7)
    - Kato, Minami -- Performance, 2015; cuid5759; 3.22 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_20)
  - Kim, K. Marie, 2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    K. Marie Kim, a member of the alt-pop duo Blank Paper and session musician, is a composer and performer based in Brooklyn, NY. She has also performed with musical groups in several other genres and created music for short films and pilots.
    - Kim, K. Marie -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5761; 3.53 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_21)
    - Kim, K. Marie -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5760; 35.84 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_33)
    - Kim, K. Marie -- Performance, 2016; cuid5762; 3.08 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_22)
  - McKenzie, Dion, 2015-2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Dion McKenzie is a Jamaican musician based in Brooklyn, NY. She is a producer and DJ who also works as a curator for two queer clubs in New York City, where she showcases her experimental club sound.
    - McKenzie, Dion -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5764; 18.27 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_24)
    - McKenzie, Dion -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5763; 219.42 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_25)
    - McKenzie, Dion -- Performance, 2015; cuid5765; 5.93 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_26)
  - Plückhan, Franziska, 2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Franziska Plückhan is a composer, producer, and performer based in Berlin, Germany. She works in the alt-pop genre under the stage name "Sissip".
    - Plückhan, Franziska -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5767; 3.49 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_34)
    - Plückhan, Franziska -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5766; 38.37 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_23)
    - Plückhan, Franziska -- Performance, 2016; cuid5768; 3.98 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_27)
  - Sasaki, Pauchi, 2016 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Bibliographical
    Pauchi Sasaki is a Peruvian-Japanese composer who utilizes her knowledge of programming to make music that combines technology with traditional instruments.
    - Sasaki, Pauchi -- Edited interview, 2016; cuid5770; 3.18 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_28)
    - Sasaki, Pauchi -- Full-length interview, 2016; cuid5769; 50.13 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_11)
    - Sasaki, Pauchi -- Performance, 2016; cuid5771; 4.07 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_29)
  - Silvestre, Gisela Fullá, 2015 (E-records FA_MSS_460)
    Gisela Fullá Silvestre is a producer, composer, and sound designer based in Brooklyn, NY. She is originally from Barcelona, Spain. She works under the stage name NOIA.
    - Silvestre, Gisela Fullá -- Edited interview, 2015; cuid5773; 4.85 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_30)
    - Silvestre, Gisela Fullá -- Full-length interview, 2015; cuid5772; 47.37 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_12)
    - Silvestre, Gisela Fullá -- Performance, 2015; cuid5774; 3.72 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_460, Object FA_MSS_460_ER_31)